Jeet Patel

(628) 777-8142 ♦ jshpatel@ucdavis.edu ♦ San Francisco, CA ♦ linkedin.com/in/jshpatel ♦ jeetp465.github.io

PROFILE

A data-driven individual with 5.5 years of analytics experience in the retail industry

Specialties: Statistical Exploration, Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Linear Optimization, A/B Testing, NLP

Technologies: Python, SQL, R, PySpark, BigQuery, Snowflake, Gurobi, PuLp, Tableau, Airflow, Git

Data Science: NumPy, Pandas, Scikit-Learn, XGBoost, PyTorch, DataProc, Vertex AI, TensorFlow, SparkML, MLOps

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

American Eagle Outfitters

San Francisco, CA

Jul 2022 - present

Data Scientist, Practicum Project

Senior Analyst, Inventory Strategy & Optimization

Sept 2021 – Jun 2022

- Piloted and built an end-to-end random forest based Lost Sales model with 65% balanced accuracy to
 estimate unit and dollar impact of missed opportunity stemming from out of stocks in the omni network
- Collaborated with the Data Science team to design a dynamic middle mile network across seven distribution centers for efficient outbound direct-to-consumer (DTC) order fulfilment using Gurobi
- Mentored a team of 5 graduate students to enhance the store-to-store transfer optimization model.
 Implemented advanced business logics to significantly elevate sell-through rate
- Engineered a proof-of-concept (POC) optimization model to propose store-to-store transfers, effectively rebalancing inventory across network of **~950** mainland US stores
- Designed the analytical layer to monitor cost and time based network KPIs for outbound DTC operations

Sears Holdings India

Pune, IND

Senior Business Analyst

Aug 2017 - Jul 2021

- Designed an MLP-LSTM based neural network followed by a Mixture Density Network to forecast demand at a product level, gaining a relative improvement of 43.6%
- Implemented Autoencoder for anomaly detection, achieving an overlap of 58% with rule-based model
- Scaled a rule-based anomaly detection model from Python to Google BigQuery, reducing the runtime by **64x**, and integrated it into a Tableau dashboard to be used by business stakeholders
- Developed a Question Answering model using Transformer architectures like Bert and Longformer for assisting users on querying terms and conditions of Sears Home Services manual
- Deduplicated & clustered ~100M Sears members into households for targeted marketing
- Developed scripts to migrate project from Teradata to BigQuery, reducing the processing time by ~50%

EDUCATION

University of California, Davis

San Francisco, CA

Master of Science, Business Analytics

Aug 2021 - Jun 2022

Indian Institute of Technology (IIT), Kanpur

Kanpur, INDJun 2013 – Jul 2017

Bachelor of Technology, Computer Science and Engineering Jun

Additional Qualifications

Selected Projects:

<u>Aspect Based Sentiment Analysis</u> - Predicted polarity of aspect terms in reviews using **LSTM** with a **55%** F-1 score <u>Real-Time Vehicle Recognition</u> - Segmented and classified vehicles from live video stream with a mean **73%** IOU

Leadership & Achievements:

- Led the curriculum committee of the Director's Student Advisory Committee (DSAC)
- Served as the coordinator of Dance Club, handling a budget of INR 100K to conduct workshops & events
- Beta Gamma Sigma, International Honor Society for Top 20% students in AASCB accredited B-Schools
- Won 1st prize in Sears Hackathon, implementing a supply chain framework on permissioned Block-Chain